I'm the weekly tech critic for the New York Times.
أنا الناقد الأسبوعي للأمور التقنية في صحيفة نيويورك تايمز
I review gadgets and stuff.
أقوم بعمل مراجعة للأدوات والأجهزة وأشياء أخرى
And mostly what good dads should be doing this time of year
واكثر ما يتوجب على الاباء الصالحون عمله في هذا الوقت من العام
is nestling with their kids and decorating the Christmas tree.
ان يقضوا الوقت مع اطفالهم ويزينوا شجرة الميلاد
What I'm mostly doing this year
واكثر ما افعله في هذا الوقت من العام
is going on cable TV and answering the same question:
هو الظهور على شبكات التلفزيون واجابة نفس السؤال
"What are the tech trends for next year?"
"ما هي توجهات التقنية في العام القادم؟"
And I'm like, "Didn't we just go through this last year?"
وابدو كمن يقول "الم نقم بالاجابة على هذا السؤال في العام السابق؟"
But I'm going to pick the one that interests me most, and that is the
لكنني سوف اقوم باختيار الموضوع الاكثر اثارة لاهتمامي,وهو
completed marriage of the cell phone and the Internet.
الإندماج الكامل بين الهواتف النقالة والإنترنت.
You know, I found that volcano on Google Images,
كما تعلمون , وجدت هذه الصورة في قسم الصور في موقع جوجل
not realizing how much it makes me look like the cover of Dianetics.
ولم الحظ ان ذلك جعلني ابدو كغلاف كتاب الديانيتكز
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Anyway, this all started a few years ago,
على اي حال, كانت البداية منذ عدة اعوام,
when they started carrying your voice over the Internet rather than over a phone line,
عندما تمكنوا من نقل الصوت على الانترنت بدلا من خطوط الهاتف
and we've come a long way since that.
ومضينا بعيدا منذ تلك اللحظة
But that was interesting in itself. This is companies like Vonage.
وذاك كان مثيرا للاهتمام في حد ذاته. شركة مثل فاونيج
Basically you take an ordinary telephone, you plug it into this little box
تقوم بوصل جهاز الهاتف المعتاد بالصندوق الصغير الذي
that they give you and the box plugs into your cable modem.
قاموا باعطائه لك ,ويتم وصل ذلك الصندوق بجهاز المودم
Now, it works just like a regular phone.
الان يعمل كما لو انه جهاز هاتف عادي
So you can pick up the phone, you hear a dial tone,
تستطيع التقاط سماعة الهاتف, وستسمع نغمة الاتصال,
but its just a fake-out. It's a WAV file of a dial tone,
لكنها عبارة عن نغمة مزيفة,مجرد ملف صوتي لنغمة الاتصال,
just to reassure you that the world hasn't ended.
ولاطمئنكم ان ذلك ليس نهاية العالم
It could be anything. It could be salsa music
يمكن استبدال صوت نغمة الطنين باي صوت اخر, موسيقى السالسا
or a comedy routine -- it doesn't matter.
او عبارة فكاهية-- لا يهم
The little box has your phone number.
ذلك الصندوق الصغير يحمل رقم هاتفك
So that's really cool -- you can take it to London or Siberia,
وذلك شيء رائع حقا-- تستطيع حمله الى لندن او سيبيريا,
and your next door neighbor can dial your home number and your phone will ring,
ويستطيع جارك الاتصال على رقم هاتفك وسوف يرن جرس هاتفك المتصل بالصندوق
because it's got everything in the box.
لان كل شيء داخل االصندوق
They've got every feature known to man in there,
لقد وضعوا فيه جميع الخصائص المعروفة للانسان,
because adding a new feature is just software.
لأن اضافة اي خاصية هي عبارة عن برنامج
And as a result of Voice Over IP --
كنتيجة لنقل الصوت عبر بروتوكول الإنترنت --
I hate that term -- Voice Over Internet --
أكره ذلك المصطلح -- الصوت عبر الإنترنت --
land-line home-phone service has gone down 30 percent in the last three years.
هبطت خدمة هاتف المنزل الأرضي بنسبة 30 في المائة في السنوات الثلاثة الأخيرة.
I mean, no self-respecting college kid has home phone service anymore.
أعني، أنه لم يعد اي طالب كلية محترم يملك خدمة هاتف منزلي
This is what college kids are more likely to have. It's the most popular
هذا ما يفضل امتلاكه طلاب الكليات. انها اشهر ..
VOIP service in the world: It's Skype.
خدمة نقل الصوت عبر بروتوكول الإنترنت في العالم: إنه سكايب.
It's a free program you download for your Mac or PC,
انه برنامج مجاني يمكنك تنزيله على حاسوبك الشخصي أو اجهزة ماكينتوش.
and you make free phone calls anywhere in the world
ثم تقوم بإجراء مكالمات هاتفية مجانية لاي مكان في العالم
The downside is that you have to wear a headset like a nerd.
الجانب السئ انك مضطر لارتداء سماعات الراس كالمهووس
It's not your phone -- it's your computer.
إنه ليس بهاتفك -- إنه حاسوبك.
But nonetheless, if you're a college kid and you have no money,
لكن مع ذلك، إذا كنت فتا جامعياً وليس لديك المال،
believe me, this is better than trying to use your cell phone.
صدقني، هذا أفضل من محاولة استخدام هاتفك النقال.
It's really cute seeing middle-aged people
إنه من اللطيف حقاً رؤية أناس في منتصف العمر
like me, try out Skype for the first time,
مثلي، يقومون بتجربة سكايب لأول مرة،
which is usually when their kid goes away for a semester abroad.
والذي عادة ما يحدث عندما يسافر أبناؤهم لأخذ فصل دراسي بالخارج.
They don't want to pay the international fees,
إنهم لا يريدون دفع رسوم الاتصالات الدولية،
so they're like, "Timmy! Is that you?"
لذا إنهم مثل "تيمي! هل هذا أنت؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's really cute.
إنه أمر طريف حقاً.
But I -- at least it was when I did it --
لكنني -- على الأقل كان كذلك عندما جربته --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I think where VOIP is really going to get interesting
أعتقد أن نقل الصوت عبر بروتوكول الإنترنت سيأخذ منحى مثير للإهتمام
is when they start putting it on cell phones.
عندما يبدأوا في دمجه في الهواتف النقالة.
Imagine if you had an ordinary cell phone,
تخبل لو أنك تملك هاتف تقليدي تقليدي،
and any time you were in a wireless hotspot --
وفي أي وقت تتواجد في منطقة بث لا سلكية --
free calls anywhere in the world,
تتصل مجانا لأي مكان في العالم،
never pay the cellular company a nickel.
لا تدفع لشركة الهاتف الخلوي فلساً.
It'd be really, really cool -- and yet,
فإن ذلك من الممكن أن يكون رائع حقاً، وايضا
even though the technology for this has been available
بالرغم من أن هذه التقنية أصبحت متاحة
for five years, incredibly,
منذ خمسة سنوات، على نحو لا يصدق،
the number of standard cell phones
فإن عدد الهواتف الخلوية الاعتيادية
offered by US carriers with free VOIP
التي تقدمها شركات الاتصالات الأمريكية وتأتي معها خدمة نقل الصوت عبر بروتوكول الإنترنت مجانية
is zero!
هي صفر.
I can't figure out why!
لا أستطيع معرفة السبب وراء ذلك!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Actually, I need to update that. There's one now.
في الواقع، أحتاج إلى تحديث ذلك، هناك واحدة الآن.
And it's so interesting that I thought I would tell you about it.
وهي مثيرة للإهتمام جداً لدرجة جعلتني أفكر أنني سوف أخبركم بها.
It comes from T-Mobile.
إنها تأتي من شركة تي - موبايل.
And I am not paid by T-Mobile.
وأنا لا أتقاضى المال من تي - موبايل.
I'm not plugging T-Mobile.
أنا لست مشتركاً بتي - موبايل.
The New York Times has very rigid policies about that.
صحيفة نيويورك لديها سياسات صارمة جداً بخصوص ذلك.
Ever since that Jayson Blair jerk ruined it for all of us.
منذ أن قام جيسون بلير الأحمق بإفساد الأمر علينا جميعاً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Basically, the reason you haven't heard about this program
في الأساس، السبب وراء أنك لم تسمع بهذا البرنامج
is because it was introduced last year
لأنه أصدر في العام الماضي
on June 29.
في 29 يونيه.
Does anyone remember what else happened on June 29 last year?
هل يتذكر أحداً منكم ماذا حدث أيضاً في 29 يونية العام الماضي؟
It was the iPhone. The iPhone came out that day.
لقد كان الآيفون.لقد ظهر الآيفون في ذلك اليوم.
I'm like, can you imagine being the
أنا أشبه، هل يمكنك تخيل أن تكون
T-Mobile PR lady? You know?
فتاة الاعلان من تي-موبايل؟ هل تتخيل؟
"Hi, we have an announcement to -- WAH!!!"
"مرحبا ,لدينا اعلان -- لااااااااااااااااااااااااا !!!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But it's actually really, really cool. You have a choice of phones,
لكن هذا أمر رائع حقاً، يمكنك الاختيار بين الهواتف،
and we're not talking smartphones --
ونحن لا نتحدث عن الهواتف الذكية --
ordinary phones, including a Blackberry, that have Wi-Fi.
الهواتف التقليدية، بما فيها البلاك بيري، الذي يحتوى على خاصية الاتصال الاسلكي
The deal is, any time you're in a Wi-Fi hotspot,
يسير الامر كالتالي، أنك عندما تكون في أي وقت في منطقة بث لا سلكية
all your calls are free.
جميع مكالماتك تجرى بالمجان.
And when you're out of the hotspot, you're on the regular cellular network.
وعندما تخرج من منطقة البث الاسلكي ،سيكون اتصالك من حلال شبكة النقال العادية.
You're thinking, "Well, how often am I in a hotspot?"
أنت تتساءل، "حسناً، كم من الوقت ساكون في نطاق الشبكة الاسلكية؟"
The answer is, "All the time!"
الإجابة هي، "طوال الوقت!"
Because they give you
لأنهم يعطونك
a regular wireless router that works with the phone,
جهاز توجيه لاسلكي عادي والذي يعمل مع الهاتف،
for your house.
لمنزلك.
Which is really ingenious, because we all know that
وذلك بارع حقا، لأننا نعلم جميعاً أن
T-Mobile is the most pathetic carrier.
تي موبايل هي الناقل الأكثر بؤسا
They have coverage like the size of my thumbnail.
لديهم تغطية أشبه بحجم اظفار ابهامي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But it's a hundred million dollars to put up one of those towers. Right?
لكن الأمر لا يتطلب أكثر من مائة مليون دولار لرفع واحد من هذه الأبراج. أليس كذلك؟
They don't have that kind of money. Instead they give each of us
إنهم لا يملكون هذا القدر من الأموال، بدلاً من ذلك يعطون كل واحد منا
a seven-dollar-and-95-cent box. They're like a stealth tower installation program.
صندوق ثمنه 7 دولارات و 95 سنت. إنها أشبه بحملة تركيب ابراج التسلل
We're putting it in our homes for them!
ونقوم بوضعها في منازلنا من أجلهم.
Anyway, they have Wi-Fi phones in Europe.
على أي حال، في اوروبا لديهم هواتف لاسلكية
But the thing that T-Mobile did that nobody's done before
لكن الشيء الذي فعلته تي-موبايل ولم يفعله احد قبلها
is, when you're on a call an you move from Wi-Fi into cellular range,
أنك عندما تجري مكالمة ثم تتحرك من نطاق الشبكة الاسلكية إلى النطاق النقال،
the call is handed off in mid-syllable,
تقطع المكالمة في منتصف الحديث،
seamlessly. I'll show you the advanced technologies
ببساطة سأريكم التقنيات المتقدمة
we use at the New York Times to test this gear.
التي نستخدمها في نيويورك تايمز لتجربة هذا الجهاز.
This is me with a camcorder on a phone
هذا هو أنا مع كاميرا اصور الهاتف
going like this.
بهذه الطريقة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
As I walk out of the house from my Wi-Fi hotspot
بينما أخرج من منزلي حيث منطقة شبكة لاسلكية
into the cellular network on a call with my wife --
إلى شبكة الهواتف النقالة أثناء مكالمة أجريها مع زوجتي --
look at the upper left. That's the Wi-Fi signal.
أنظر إلى أعلى اليسار. هذا هو مكان إشارة الواي فاي.
(Video): Jennifer Pogue: Hello?
(فيديو): جينيفر بوج: مرحباً؟
David Pogue: Hi babes, it's me.
ديفيد بوج: أهلا عزيزتي، هذا أنا.
JP: Oh, hi darling, how are you?
ج ب: أهلاً عزيزي، كيف حالك؟
DP: You're on Wi-Fi. How does it sound?
د ب: أنت على إرسال واي فاي. كيف يبدو الأمر؟
JP: Oh, it sounds pretty good.
ج ب: يبدو الأمر رائعاً جداً.
Now, I'm leaving the house. DP: I'm going for a walk -- do you mind?
د ب: الآن، أنا أغادر المنزل. سأذهب لنزهة -- هل تمانعين؟
JP: No not at all. I'm having a great day with the kids.
ج ب: لا أمانع على الاطلاق. انا امضي يوما رائعا مع الاولاد.
DP: What are you guys doing?
د.ب.: ماذا تفعلون؟
Right there!
لاحظوا هنا !
It just changed to the cellular tower in mid-call.
لقد انتقلت المكالمة الى برج الهاتف النقال في منتصف المكالمة
I don't know why my wife says I never listen to her. I don't get that.
لا اعلم لماذا تقول زوجتي انني لا استمع لها ابدا. لم استوعب ذلك
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The bottom line is that the boundaries,
بيت القصيد في كل ذلك هو الحدود
because of the Internet plus cell phone, are melting.
لأن الانترنت والهاتف الخلوي ينصهران
The cool thing about the T-Mobile phones
الشيء اللطيف بخصوص هواتف تي-موبايل
is that although switching technologies is very advanced,
هو انه بالرغم من ان تقنية الانتقال متقدمة جدا
the billing technology has not caught up.
فان تقنية الفواتير لم تلحق بها
So what I mean is that you can start a call
ما اعنيه هو انه بامكانك بدء مكالمة
in your house in the Wi-Fi hotspot,
في داخل منزلك في نطاق ال واي- فاي
you can get in your car and talk until the battery's dead --
بامكانك ركوب السيارة ومواصلة المكالمة حتى نفاذ البطارية--
which would be like 10 minutes --
الذي لن يستمر اكثر من عشر دقائق
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And the call will continue to be free.
وستكون تلك المكالمة مجانية بالكامل
Because they don't, they haven't --
لانهم لم , لم يمتلكون--
well, no, wait! Not so fast.
حسنا, انتظروا ليس بتلك السرعة
It also works the other way.
هذه العملية تتم ايضا بالاتجاه الاخر
So if you start a call on your cellular network
اذا بدات مكالمة خلال شبكة الخليوي
and you come home, you keep being billed.
ودخلت منزلك , سوف تحتسب عليك الفواتير
Which is why most people with this service
وهاذا ما يفسر لماذا كل الاشخاص الذين لديهم تلك الخدمة
get into the habit of saying,
عادة ما يقولون
"Hey, I just got home. Can I call you right back?"
"لحظة, لقد وصلت للتو للمنزل. هل بامكاني اعادة الاتصال بك"
Now you get it.
الان تفهمون لماذا.
It's also true that if you use one of these phones overseas,
وايضا تلك حقيقة انه اذا استخدمت تلك الهواتف خارج البلاد
it doesn't know what Internet hotspot you're in.
لا تعلم تلك الهواتف على اي شبكة انترنت انت متصل
On the Internet nobody knows you're a dog,
على الانترنت لن يعلم احد انك كلب
right? Nobody knows you're in Pakistan.
صحيح؟ لا يعلم احد انك في باكستان
You can make free unlimited calls
يمكنك اجراء مكالمات مجانية بلا بحدود
home to the US with these phones. So, very, very interesting.
الى الولايات المتحدة باستخدام تلك الهواتف. ذلك حقا حقا مثير للاهتمام
This is another favorite of mine.
شيئ اخر مفضل بالنسبة لي.
Does anyone here have a working cell phone
هل يمتلك احد هنا هاتف نقال يعمل
that's on, with coverage, who can make a call right now without a lot of fussing?
قيد التشغيل, بتغطية ارسال, وبامكانه عمل اتصال الان بدون تلكؤ؟
OK. Would you call me please right now? [Phone number given.]
حسنا.هللا اتصلت بي الان ؟
And don't you all call me at three a.m. asking me to fix your printer.
ولا تتصلوا بي جميعا الساعة الثالثة فجرا تطلبون مني اصلاح طابعتكم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I have two cell phones, so this going to be very odd, if it works.
لدي هاتفين خلويين, سيكون جدا غريب اذا عملا
I should know not to do technology demos
علي ان اعلم ان لا اعمل تجارب تكنلوجية
in front of an audience. It's just, like, absurd.
امام جمهور, ذلك سيكون ذلك سخيفا.
This one is going off. And -- oh, I have the ringer off. Tsh! Great.
يتم اغلاق هذا و-- اوه لقد اغلقت الرنين. عظيم.
Anyway, this one is also going off. So they're both ringing at the same time.
على اي حال , هذا ايضا يغلق. اذا هما يرنان في نفس الوقت
Excuse me one second.
اعذروني لحظة
Hello?
مرحبا؟
Oh. Where are you calling from?
اوه. من اين تتصل؟
No, no just kidding. There he is. Thank you very much for doing that.
لا . انني امزح. هاهو هناك.شكرا جزيلا لعمل هذا
I didn't even know it was you -- I was looking at this guy.
لم اكن حتى اعلم انه انت. كنت انظر لهذا الرجل
Oh great! Yeah. Yeah you can all stop calling now!
حسنا عظيم ! نعم. نعم انتم توقفو عن الاتصال بي الان!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
All right! We've made the point.
حسنا لقد اوصلنا المعلومة
All right. Ringer off. Everyone wants in on the action.
حسنا . اغلاق الرنين. الجميع يرغب بالمساهمة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So this is Grand Central at work -- it's a --
هذا تطبيق لخدمة بدالة مركزية -- انها--
oh, for gods sake!
اوه, لاجل الله
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I have your numbers now!
الان لدي ارقامكم!
You will pay.
ستدفعون
Grand Central is this really brilliant idea
البدالة المركزية هي فعلا فكرة ذكية
where they give you a new phone number,
حيث يعطونك رقم جديد
and then at that point one phone number rings all your phones at once.
ومن ثم عندما يرن ذلك الرقم يجعل جميع هواتفك ترن في نفس الوقت
Your home phone, your work phone, your cell phone, your yacht phone
هاتف منزلك,هاتف عملك,هاتفك الخلوي,هاتف يختك.
(this is the EG crowd).
هذا تجمع المؤتمر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The beauty of that is you never miss a call.
الجميل في ذلك انك لن تفوت اي اتصال
I know a lot of you are like,
اعلم ان كثيرا منكم سيمتعضون,
"Ooh, I don't want to be reached at any hour."
"لا اريد ان يتم الوصول الي في اي ساعة"
But the beauty is it's all going through the internet,
لكن الجميل في الامر ان كل ذلك يتم من خلال الانترنت
so you get all of these really cool features --
وبالتالي تحصل على عديد من المزايا الرائعة--
like you can say, I want these people to be able to call me only during these hours.
كأن تقول, اريد هؤلاء الاشخاص ان يتصلو بي فقط خلال هذه الاوقات.
And I want these people to hear this greeting,
واريد هؤلاء الاشخاص ان يستمعوا لهذا الترحيب
"Hi boss, I'm out making us both some money. Leave a message."
"اهلا مديري, انا في الخارج احصل على بعض المال لكلانا. اترك رسالة."
And then your wife calls, and, "Hi honey, leave me a message."
وعندما تتصل زوجتك ," مرجبا عزيزتي, اتركي رسالة"
Very, very customizable.
قابل للتخصيص جدا
Google bought it, and they've been working on it for a year.
اشترته شركة جوجل, وهم يعملون عليه منذ عام
They're supposed to come out with it very shortly in a public method.
ومن المفترض ان يظهر قريبا لاستخدام الجميع
By the way, this is something that really bothers me.
بالمناسبة,هذا شيء يقلقني حقا.
I don't know if you realize this. When you call 411 on your cell phone,
لا اعلم اذا كنتم قد لاحظتم هذا. عندما تتصلون بالرقم 411 من هاتفكم النقال
they charge you two bucks.
يحتسبون عليك دولارين
Did you know that? It's an outrage.
هل لاحظتم ذلك؟انها اهانة
I actually got a photograph of the Verizon employee right there.
وفي الواقع قد حصلت على صورة لموظف شركة فيريزون هناك.
I'm going to tell you how to avoid that now.
الان سـأخبرك كيف تتفادى ذلك
What you're going to use is Google Cellular.
ما سوف تستخدمه هو شريحة جوجل
It's totally free -- there's not even ads.
انه مجاني كليا -- ولا يحتوي على إعلانات
If you know how to send a text message, you can get the same information for free.
اذا كنت تعلم كيف ترسل رسال نصية, ستحصل على نفس المعلومة بالمجان
I'm about to change your life. So here's me doing it.
انني على وشك تغيير حياتكم.وها أنا اقوم بذلك
You send a text message to the word "Google,"
تحتاج لارسال كلمة "جوجل"
which turns out to be 46645.
والتي ستتحول الى 46645
Leave off the last "e" for savings.
اترك الحرف الاخير للادخار
Anyway, so lets say you need a drugstore near Chicago.
على اي حال, لنقل انك تريد صديلية بالقرب من شيكاجو.
You type "pharmacy Chicago," or the zip code.
تكتب "صيدلية شيكاجو" او الرمز البريدي
You hit send, and in five seconds,
تضغط على ارسال , وخلال خمس ثواني,
they will send you back the two closest drugstores,
سيرسلون لك اقرب صيدليتين
complete with name address and phone number.
متضمنة الاسم والعنوان ورقم الهاتف
Here it comes.
هاقد وصلت
And it's already written down -- so, like, if you're driving,
وهي مكتوبة-- فاذا كنت تقود سيارتك,
you don't have to do one of these things, "Uh huh, uh huh, uh huh."
لا داعي لترديد الكللمات " حسنا ,نعم , واضح"
It works with weather, too.
انها تعمل ايضا لمعرفة حالة الطقس
You can say "Weather," and the name of the city you're going to travel to.
يمكنك القول " طقس" واسم المدينة التي سوف تسافر اليها.
And then in five seconds, they send you back
وفي خلال خمس ثواني سيرسلون اليك
the complete weather forecast for that town.
توقعات كاملة لحالة الطقس في تلك المدينة
Shortly I'll tell you why I was in Milan.
بعد قليل ساخبركم لماذا كنت في ميلان.
Here we go. And those are just the beginning.
هانحن نبدا. وتلك هي البداية فقط
These are all the different things that you can text to Google and they will --
تلك هي الاشياء التي يمكن ارسالها الى جوجل وسوف يقومون--
yeah! You're all trying to write this down.
اعلم انكم جميعا تحاولون كتابتها
That's cute. I do have an email address. You can just ask me.
ذلك رائع. لدي عنوان بريد الكتروني. يمكنكم الاستفسار
It's absolutely phenomenal. The only downside
انها حقا ظاهرة. الجانب السلبي الوحيد
is that it requires you to know how to text --
هو انه يتوجب عليك ان ترسل--
send a text message. Nobody over 40 knows how to do that.
ترسل رسالة نصية. لا احد تجاوز الاربعين يستطيع عمل ذلك
So I'm going to teach you something even better.
لذلك ساعلمكم شيئا افضل.
This is called Google Info.
انها تسمى معلومات جوجل
They've just launched this voice-activated version of the same thing.
لقد اطلقوا للتو النسخة الصوتية لتلك الخدمة
It's speech recognition like you've never heard before.
انها تعتمد على ادراك الكلام بطريقة لم يسبق لها مثيل
So lets say I'm in Monterey,
لنفترض انني في مونتري
and I want what?
وماذا اريد؟
I want to find what? Bagels. OK.
وماذا اريد ان اجد؟حسنا خبز
Google: Say the business and the city and state.
جوجل: قل النشاط والمدينة والولاية.
DP: Bagels, Monterey, California.
د.ب. خبز, مونتري,كاليفورنيا
I got the Chinese line.
حصلت على الخط الصيني
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Google: Bagels, Monterey, California.
جوجل: خبز,مونتري, كاليفورنيا
Top eight results: Number one,
اول ثمانية نتائج: رقم واحد
Bagel Bakery on El Dorado Street.
مخابز باجل , في شارع ال درادو
To select number one, you can press one or say "number one."
لاختيار رقم واحد اضغط 1 او قل "رقم واحد"
Number two: Bagel Bakery, commissary department.
رقم اثنان: مخابز باجل, دائرة كوميساري
Number Two. Number Two. Two.
الرقم اثنان. الرقم اثنان. اثنان.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Why do I listen to people in the audience?
لماذا اصغي للجماهير
Well anyway -- oh! Here we go!
حسنا على اي حال-- لحظة هاي تعمل
Google: ... commissary department on McClellan Avenue, Monterey.
جوجل... دائرة كوميساري في مكليلان افينو, مونتيري
I'll connect you, or say "details," or "go back."
ساقوم بوصلك, او قل" معلومات" او " عودة"
DP: He's connecting me! He doesn't even tell me the phone number.
د. ب. انه يقوم بوصلي , انه لم يخبرني رقم الهاتف اصلا
He's just connecting me directly. It's like having a personal valet.
انه يقوم بوصلي مباشرة. كما لو ان لديك خادم شخصي
Google: Hold on.
جوجل: انتظر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
DP: Hi, could I have 400 with a schmear?
د.ب. : مرحبا, هل استطيع الحصول على 400 بكريمة الجبنة؟
No, no, no -- just kidding, no no.
لا لا لا لا لا-- انني امزح, لا لا لا
So anyway, you never even find out the number.
اذا على اي حال,انت حتى لم تحصل على الرقم ابدا
It's just so amazing.
ذلك فعلا رائع
And it has incredible, incredible accuracy.
وذو دقة فائقة جدا
This is even more amazing. Put this in your speed dial.
هذا ايضا مدهش .ضع هذا في الاتصال السريع؟
This you can ask by voice any question.
يمكنك ان تسال اي سؤال باستخدام الصوت
Who won the 1958 World Series?
من فاز في بطولة العالم 1958؟
What's the recipe for a certain cocktail?
ما هي وصفة عمل كوكتيل؟
It's absolutely amazing -- and they text you back the answer.
ذلك فعلا مدهش--ويرسلون اليك الاجابة
I tried this this morning just to make sure it's still alive.
لقد جربتها هذا الصباح فقط للتاكد من وجود الخدمة
"Which actors have played James Bond?"
من هم الممثلين الذين لعبوا دور جيمس بوند؟
They text me back this: "Sean Connery,
وارسلو الي هذا: شين كونري
George Lazenby, Roger Moore, Timothy Dalton, Pierce Brosnan, Daniel Craig."
جورج لازنبي,روجر مور,تيومثي دالتون, بيرس بروسنان, دانيال كرايج
Right! And then I was trying to pretend I was like a Valley girl.
صحيح! حاولت ان اتظاهر باني فتاة مدللة
I'm like, "What's the word that means you know, like,
"ما هي الكلمة التي تعني ,مثل,
when the sun, the moon and the earth are, like, all in a line?"
عندما يكون الشمس والقمر والارض جميعهم,مثل, على نفس الخط؟"
Just to see how the recognition was.
فقط لارى كيف كيف يتم ادراك السؤال.
They texted me back, "It's called a syzygy."
وارسلو لي ,"انه يسمى الاقتران"
Which I knew, because it's the word that won me the Ohio spelling bee in 1976.
وانا عرفت ذلك,لان هذه الكلمة جعلتني اربح مسابقة التهجئة في اوهايو عام 1976.
You know, there's a lot of people wondering, "How on earth are they going to
تعلمون, الكثير من الناس يفكرون "كيف يمكنهم ان
make money doing this?" And the answer is: look at the last line.
يجنوا الاموال بعمل ذلك؟" والاجابة هي: انظر الى السطر الاخير.
They put this teeny-weeny little ad, about 10 characters long.
لقد وضعو اعلان صغير جدا , مكون من عشرة احرف
And a lot of people also want to know, "How does it work?
والكثير من الناس يريدون معرفة, " كيف تعمل ؟
How can it be so good? It's as though there is a human being
كيف هي بتلك الجودة؟ انها تبدو كما لو ان انسانا
on the other end of the line."
على الطرف الاخر من الخط."
Because there is one!
بالفعل يوجد
They have 10,000 people
لديهم 10,000 شخص
who are being paid 20 cents per answer.
يدفع لهم 20 سنت لكل اجابة
As you can imagine, it's college kids and old people.
يمكنك ان تتخيل, انهم طلبة الجامعة والمسنين
That's who can afford to do that.
اولائك من يمكنهم تحمل عمل ذلك
But it's a human being on the line. And it's gotten me out of so many
لكن انه انسان على الخط,وقد استطاعوا فهمي مرارا
tough positions like, "When's the last flight out of Chicago?"
في حالات مثل ," ما هي اخر رحلة تغادر الى شيكاجو"
You know. It's just absolutely amazing.
تعلمون. انها فعلا مدهشة
Another thing that really bothers me about cell phones today --
شيئ اخر حقا يزعجني اليوم بخصوص الهواتف النقالة --
this is probably my biggest pet peeve in all of technology.
هذه تقريبا اكبر معاناة تغيظني في التقنية
When I call to leave you a message,
عندما اتصل لاترك لك رسالة,
I get 15 seconds of instructions
اجد 15 ثانية من التعليمات
from a third-grade teacher on Ambien!
من معلم من الدرجة الثالثة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"To page this person ... "
"لاشعار هذا الشخص..."
Page? What is this, 1975?
اشعار؟؟؟ ماذا هل هذه عام 1975؟
Nobody has pagers anymore.
لم يعد احد يحمل اجهزة اشعار.
"You may begin speaking at the tone.
"يمكنك الكلام بعد سماع الصافرة.
When you have finished recording,
عندما تنتهي من التسجيل,
you may hang up." No!
يمكنك انهاء المكالمة.: لا!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And then it gets worse:
ويصبح الامر اكثر سوءا:
when I call to retrieve my messages,
عندما اتصل لاستلم رسائلي,
first of all: "You have 87 messages.
في البداية:"لديك 87 رسالة.
To listen to your messages ... "
للاستماع لرسائلك..."
Why else am I calling?
لمذا انا اتصل اذا؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Of course I want to listen to the messages!
بالطبع اريد ان استمع لرسائلي!
Oh! You all have cell phones too.
ياالهي! ايضا.انتم جميعا لديكم هواتف نقالة
So last year I went to Milan, Italy,
في العام المضي ذهبت الى ميلان ,ايطاليا
and I got to speak to an audience
وكنت اتحدث الى جمهور
of cellular executives from 200 countries around the world.
من مدراء شركات الهواتف الخلوية من 200 دولة حول العالم
And I said as a joke -- as a joke, I said,
وقلت على سبيل المزاح-- على سبيل المزاح, قلت,
"I did the math. Verizon has 70 million customers.
"لقد قمت بالحسابات. شركة فيريزون لديها 70 مليون مشترك.
If you check your voicemail twice a day,
اذا تفحصوا رسائلهم الصوتية مرتين في اليوم,
that's 100 million dollars a year.
ذلك يعني 100 مليون دولار سنويا.
I bet you guys are doing this just to run up our airtime, aren't you?"
اراهن انكم تفعلون هذا لايصال البث الينا, اليس كذلك؟"
No chuckle. They're like this --
لم يبتسموا. واومأوا برؤسهم هكذا--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Where is the outrage, people? Rise up!
اين الغاضبون, ارفعو ايديكم!
Sorry. I'm not bitter.
اسف ,انا لست لاذع.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So now I'm going to tell you how to get out of that.
الان سوف اخبركم كيف تتخلصون من ذلك.
There are these services that transcribe
هناك تلك الخدمات التي تحول
your voicemail into text.
رسائلك الصوتيه الى نصوص
And they send it either to your email
ويرسلونها اما الى بريدك الالكتروني
or as text messages to your phone.
او كرسالة نصية الى هاتفك
It is a life-changer.
انها تغير نمط الحياة
And by the way, they don't always get the words right,
وبالمناسبة ,انهم لا يتمكنون دوما من فهم الكلمات بشكل صحيح,
because it's over the phone and all that.
لانها تكون عن طريق الهاتف وهكذا
So they attach the audio file at the bottom of the email
لذلك هم يرفقون ملف صوتي في اسفل البريد الالكتروني
so you can listen to double-check.
بحيث يمكنك الاستماع لزيادة التحقق
The services are called things like Spinvox,
تلك الخدمات لها مسميات مختلفة مثل سبينفوكس
Phonetag -- this is the one I use --
فونتاج--وهذه هي التي استخدمها--
Callwave. A lot of people say, "How are they doing this?
كول ويف. الكثير يسالون ,"كيف يقومون بذلك؟
I don't really want people listening in to my calls."
لا ارغب ان يستمع الناس لمكالماتي."
The executives at these companies told me,
المدراء في تلك الشركات اخبروني,
"Well we use a proprietary B-to-B, best-of-breed, peer-to-peer soluti -- " you know.
"حسنا نحن نستخدم نظريات مختلفة وحلول--" تعلمون ما اعني
I think basically it's like these guys in India with headsets, you know, listening in.
اعتقد ان اؤلئك الموظفين في الهند يضعون سماعات الراس, تعلمون ما اعني, ويستمعون.
The reason I think that is that
ما يجعلني اعتقد ان ذلك هو ما يحدث
on the first day I tried one of these services,
في اول يوم قمت بتجربة احدى تلك الخدمات
I got two voicemail messages. One was from a guy named Michael Stevenson,
تلقيت رسالتين صوتيتين . واحدة من شخص يسمى مايكل ستيفينسون,
which shouldn't be that hard to transcribe, and it was misspelled.
الأسم ليس بتلك الصعوبة ليتم تهجئته , ولم يتم تهجئته بالشكل الصحيح
The other was from my video producer at the Times, whose name is Vijaiy Singh,
والرسالة الاخرى من منتج الفيديو الخاص بي في صحيفة النيويورك تايمز, واسمه فيجاي
with the silent 'h'. Nailed that one.
بحرف "هاء" صامت.تم تهجئته تماما
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So you be the judge.
ستكونون انتم الحكام
Anyway, this service, Callwave, promises
على اي حال, خدمة ال كول ويف , تؤكد
that it's all software -- nobody is listening to your messages.
ان كل ذلك يتم باستخدام البرامج-- لا احد يقوم بالاستماع الى رسائلك.
And they also promise that they're going to transcribe only the gist
وهم يؤكدون ايضا انهم يقومون بتحويل جوهر
of your messages.
رسائلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So I thought I'd see how that goes.
فكرت في معرفة كيف تسير الامور
This is me testing it out.
هذا انا اختبر الخدمة
(Video): Hello, this is Michael.
(مقطع فيديو):مرحبا.انا مايكل.
Hope you're doing well. I'm fine here. Everything's good.
اتمنى ان كل شيئ على ما يرام, انا هنا بخير, كل شيئ جيد.
Hey, I was walking along the street and the sky was blue.
اسمعي, كنت امشي في الطريق وكانت السماء زرقاء.
And your daughter broke her leg at soccer practice.
وابنتك كسرت ساقها في تدريب كرة القدم.
I'm going to have a sandwich for lunch.
سأتناول شطيرة على الغداء
She's in room -- emergency room 53W.
انها في في غرفة-- غرفة طوارئ رقم 53 و.
OK, talk to you later -- bye.
حسنا, ساتحدث اليك لاحقا--وداعا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I love my job.
احب عملي
So a couple minutes later, this I got by email.
بعد دقيقتين, تلقيت هذا البريد الالكتروني
It's a very good transcription. But a couple minutes after that,
لقد كان تحويلا رائعا للنص,لكن بعد دقيقتين
I got the text message version. Now remember,
تلقيت نسخة الرسالة النصية. الان تذكروا
a text message can only be 160 characters long.
الرسالة النصية يمكن انت تحتوي 160 حرف فقط
So it had better be the gist of the gist, right?
من الافضل انت تحتوي جوهر الجوهر. صحيح؟
I'm not kidding you. The message said,
انني لا امزح, الرسالة كانت تقول,
"Was walking along the street" and "sky was blue" and "emergency"!
"كنت امشي على الطريق "و " كانت السماء زرقاء"و"طوارئ"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
What the f -- ?
ذلك فعلا --؟
Well I guess that was the gist.
استطيع التخمين ان ذلك هو الجوهر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And lastly, I just have to talk about this one.
واخيرا, يجب ان اتكلم عن هذه.
This is my favorite of all time. It's called Popularitydialer.com.
انها المفضلة لدي دوما. انها تسمى Popularitydialer.com.
Basically, you're going to go on some
بشكل اساسي.انتم معرضون لبعض المواقف
iffy date, or a potentially bad meeting.
مواعيد غير مرتبة, او اجتماع سيء
So you go and you type in your phone number,
فتقوم بزيارة الموقع وكتابة رقم هاتفك
and at the exact minute where you want to be called --
وفي الوقت المحدد الذي ترغب في ان تتلقى اتصال
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And at that moment your phone will ring.
في تلك الحظة سوف يرن جرس هاتفك
And you're like, "I'm sorry. I've got to take this."
وسوف تبدو كما لو انك تقول ,"انا اسف, يجب ان ارد على هذا الاتصال"
The really beautiful thing is,
الشيء الجميل في الموضوع,
you know how when somebody's sitting next to you, sometimes they can sort of
تعلمون عندما يجلس شخص بجواركم, بعض الاحيان الى حد ما
hear a little bit of the caller.
يسمعون قليلا من صوت المتصل
So they give you a choice
ولذلك يعطونك الخيار
of what you want to hear on the other end.
ماذا تريد ان تسمع على الطرف الاخر
Here's the girlfriend.
هذا هو صوت الصديقة
Phone: Hey you, what's going on?
المتصل: مرحبا, كيف تسير الامور؟
DP: I'm kinda, like, giving a talk right now.
د.ب. :انني ادلي بحديث الان.
Phone: Well, that's good.
المتصل: هذا جيد.
DP: What are you doing?
د.ب.: ماذا تفعلين؟
Phone: I was just wondering what you were up to.
المتصل: فقط كنت افكر مالذي تفعله.
DP: Right, I can't really talk right now.
د.ب. : فعلا لا استطيع التحدث الان.
This is the -- I love this -- the boss call.
هذا -- احب هذا-- اتصال المدير
Phone: Hey, this is Mr. Johnson calling from the office.
المتصل: مرحبا , انا السيد جونسون اتصل بك من المكتب.
DP: Oh, hi, sir.
د.ب. اهلا سيدي.
Phone: Did you complete that thing about a month ago? That photocopier training?
المتصل: هل اتتمت ذلك الامر الموكل لك منذ شهر؟ التدريب على الة التصوير؟
DP: Oh -- sorry I forgot.
د.ب. -- اسف لقد نسيت.
Phone: Yeah, well so when was the last time you used the photocopier?
المتصل: نعم, متى كانت اخر مرة استخدمت فيه الة التصوير؟
DP: It was like three weeks ago.
د.ب.: كان ذلك منذ ثلاث أسابيع مضت
Phone: Well, I don't know if you heard, you might have heard from Lenny, but --
المتصل: حسنا, لا اعلم اذا كنت قد سمعت, لربما سمعت من ليني.لكن--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I think the biggest change when Internet met phone
اعتقد ان اكبر تغيير نتج عن لقاء الهاتف والانترنت
was with the iPhone.
كان مع اي فون
Not my finest moment in New York Times journalism.
لم تكن الطف لحظاتي في صحيفة ال نيويورك تايمز
It was when in the fall of 2006,
كان ذلك في خريف 2006
I explained why Apple would never do a cell phone.
وضحت لماذا لن تقوم شركة ابل بعمل هاتف نقال
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I looked like a moron. However, my logic was good,
بدوت كالمغفل.على اي حال, كان منطقي جيدا.
because -- I don't know if you realize this, but -- until the iPhone came along,
لانه لا اعلم اذا كنتم قد لاحظتم ذلك.لكن الى لحظة ظهور اي فون
the carriers -- Verizon, AT&amp;T, Cingular --
شركات الاتصالات--فيريزون,اي تي اند تي , سينجولار--
held veto power over every aspect
استخدموا قوة الفيتو في مواجهة اي إتجاه
of every design of every phone.
لأي تصميم لأي هاتف
I know the people who worked on the Treo.
انا اعرف الاشخاص الذين عملوا في شركة تريو
They went around to these carriers and said,
لقد طافوا بشركات الاتصالات وقالوا لهم,
"Look at these cool features." And Verizon is like, "Hmm, no.
"انظرو هذه خاصية رائعة." واجابت فيريزون " حسنا , لا.
I don't think so."
"لا نعتقد ذلك."
It was not very conducive to innovation.
ذلك لم يكن مشجعا على الابتكار
What I didn't anticipate was that Steve Jobs
ما لم اتوقعه هو ان ستيف جوبس
went around and said, "Tell you what -- I'll give you a five-year exclusive
طاف وقال " تعرفون ماذا-- ساعطيكم احتكارا لمدة خمسة سنوات
if you'll let me design this phone in peace --
اذا تركتموني اصمم هذا الهاتف بسلام--
and you won't even see it till it's done."
ولن تشاهدوه حتى الانتهاء من تنفيذه"
Actually, even so, he was turned down by Verizon and others.
في الواقع,ايضا,تم رفض عرضه من قبل فيريزون واخرون.
Finally Cingular said OK.
واخيرا قبلته سينجولار.
I'm going to talk about the effect of the iPhone.
سوف اتحدث عن تأثير اي فون
Please don't corner me at the party tonight
ارجوكم لا تحشروني في زاوية في حفلة هذا المساء
and go, "What are you? An Apple fan boy?"
وتقولون " من انت؟ مشجع لشركة ابل؟"
- you know. I'm not.
-تعلمون انني لست من المشجعين
You can see what I said about it. It's a flawed masterpiece.
تستطيعون ان ترون ماذا قلت بهذا الخصوص.كانت تلك تحفة معيبة.
It's got bad things and good things. Lets all acknowledge that right now.
لديها جوانب سيئة وجوانب جيدة. لنقر جميعنا بذلك الان.
But it did change a few things. The first thing it changed
لكن قد غيرت بعض الاشياء. واول تلك الاشياء
was that all those carriers saw
ان شركات الاتصالات عرفوا
that they sold 10 million of these things in a year.
انهم باعوا 10 مليون من ذلك الشيئ خلال سنة .
And they said, "Oh my gosh, maybe we've been doing it wrong.
وقالو ,"يالهي, ربما كنا مخطئين.
Maybe we should let phone designers design the phones."
ربما كان من الافضل ان نترك مصممي الهواتف يقومون بتصميم الهاتف"
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Another thing was that it let 10 million people,
الشيء الاخر انه مكن 10 مليون شخص
for the first time, experience being online all the time.
لاول مرة , تجربة الاتصال بالانترنت طوال الوقت
Not using these 60-dollar-a-month
بدون استخدام تلك الاشتراكات الشهرية فئة 60 دولار
cellular cards for their laptops.
لشرائحهم النقالة لاستخدامها لاجهزتهم المحمولة
I don't understand why we're not there yet.
لا اعلم لماذا لم نصل هناك حتى الان
When I'm an old man, I'm going to tell my grandchildren,
عندما اكون كهلا. سوف اخبر احفادي
"When I was your age, if I wanted to check my email,
"عندما كنت في مثل عمركم, اذا اردت قراءة بريدي الالكتروني,
I used to drive around town looking for a coffee shop. I did!"
اعتدت ان اجوب المدينة بحثا عن مقهى انترنت. فعلت ذلك"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"We had wireless base stations that could
"كان لدينا محطات لاسلكية تستطيع
broadcast -- yay, about 150 feet across."
البث--نعم, في مجال حوالي 150 قدم"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's absurd. We have power outlets
ذلك سخيف, لدينا مقبس كهرباء
in every room of every building. We have running water.
في كل غرفة في كل بناية. لدينا مياه جارية.
What's the problem?
ما المشكلة؟
Anyway -- but this teaches people what it's like.
عل اي حال-- هذا علّم الناس ماهية الموضوع
You have to go to YouTube
يجب ان تذهبو الى موقع اليوتيوب
and type in "iPhone Shuffle."
وابحثوا عن "iphone shuffle"
This guy did a mock video of one
عمل هذا الرجل مقطع فيديو ساخر عن
that's one inch square, like the real iPod Shuffle.
ذلك الشئ ذو البوصة المربعة , يبدو كانه اي بود شافيل حقيقي
It's like, "It only has one button.
يبدو كانه,"يحتوي على مفتاح واحد.
Touch it and it dials a number at random."
المسه وسيقوم بالاتصال عشوائيا برقم."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Who the hell is this?"
"من هذا ؟"
But the other thing it did
لكن الشيء الاخر الذي فعله
is it opened up this idea of an app store.
انه ابرز فكرة متجر البرامج
It downloads right to the phone.
يتم تحميله مباشرة الى الهاتف
And you can use the tilt sensor
وبامكانك استخدام محاس جهاز الاستشعار
to steer this car using this game.
لتوجيه السيارة في هذه اللعبة.
These programs can use all the components
تلك البرامج يمكنها استخدام جميع مكونات
of the iPhone -- the touch screen.
جهاز اي فون -- شاشة اللمس.
This is the Etch-A-Sketch program -- the theme of EG 2008.
هذا برنامج ارسم-رسمة التمظهر العام من اي جي 2008
You know how you erase it?
هل تعرفون كيف تمسحونه؟
Of course. You shake it.
بالطبع. تهزها.
Right, of course. We shake it to erase, like this.
صحيح, بالطبع نهزها لنمسح. هكذا.
They have 10,000 of these programs.
لديهم 10 الاف من تلك البرامج.
This is the translator program. They have every language in the world.
هذا هو برنامج المترجم. لديهم كل لغة في العالم.
You type in what you want, and it gives you the translation.
تكتب ما تريد, وتعطيك الترجمة.
This is amazing. This is Midomi.
هذا مدهش. هذه ميدومي
A song is running through your head --
هناك اغنية في راسك--
you sing it into the thing:
تغنيها لهذا الشيئ
do do do do do, da da da da da da, da dum ...
تيرا تيرا تيرا تيرا تير ,ترا ترا ترا ترا ترا ترا...
OK, you tap, "Done" and it will find out the song and play it for you.
حسنا, تختار, " تم" وسوف تجد لك الاغنية وتشغلها لك.
I know. It's insane, right?
اعلم. انه جنون, صحيح؟
This is Pandora. Free Internet radio. Not just free Internet radio --
هذا هو برنامج باندورا. اذاعة انترنت مجانية. ليس فقط اذاعة انترنت مجانية--
you type in a band or a song name.
تكتب اسم فرقة او اغنية.
It will immediately play you that song or that band.
فورا سوف تشغل لك الاغنية او الفرقة
It has a thumbs-up and a thumbs-down.
هناك مفاتيح فوق ومفاتيح اسفل
You say if you like this song or not.
تحدد اذا ما اعجبتك الاغنية او لا.
If you like it, it tries another song on you
اذا اعجبتك, سوف تسمعك اغنية اخرى.
from a different band, with the same instrumentation, vocals,
من فرقة اخرى. بنفس الادوات, والغناء
theme and tempo.
الطابع, والايقاع.
If you like that one, or don't like it,
اذا اعجبتك , او لم تعجبك,
you do thumbs-up and thumbs-down. Over time it tailors the songs
تضغط على مفتاح اعلى ومفتاح اسفل . بمرور الوقت تنظم الاغاني.
so that it completely stops playing bad songs.
بحيث انها تتوقف عن تشغيل الاغاني السيئة تماما.
It eventually only plays songs you like.
في نهاية المطاف سوف تشغل الاغاني التي تحبها.
This is Urbanspoon. You're in a city. It knows from GPS where you're standing.
هذا برنامج اوربانسبون . انت في مدينة ما .سوف يحدد مكانك باستخدام نظام تحديد المواقع.
You want to find a place to eat. You shake it.
انت تريد مكانا لتأكل فيه. تفوم بهزه.
It proposes a restaurant.
يقدم لك عرض لاحد المطاعم؟
It gives you the price, and the location and ratings.
يعطيك السعر. والموقع والتقييم
Video: I'm not going all the way to Flushing.
(فيديو) :انا لن اقطع تلك المسافة الى فلاشينج.
Anyway, just amazing, amazing things.
على اي حال,مدهش, فعلا اشياء مدهشة
Of course, its not just about the iPhone.
بالطبع,هذا كله ليس بخصوص اي فون فقط.
The iPhone broke the dyke, the wall.
اي فون قام بكسر السد, الجدار.
But now it's everybody else. So Google has done their own Android operating system
لكن الان الجميع. قامت جوجل بعمل نظام التشغيل "أندرويد" الخاص بهم.
that will soon be on handsets -- phones from 34 companies.
قريبا سيكون على اجهزة النقال --هواتف من 34 شركة
Touch screen -- very, very nice.
شاشة قابلة للمس-- جميل جدا جدا
Also with its own app store, where you can download programs.
ايضا بسوق البرامج الخاصة بها.حيث يمكنك تحميل البرامج.
This is amazing. In the wake of all this,
هذا رائع. في ظل كل هذا
Verizon, the most calcified, corporate,
فيريزون, الشركة الاكثر تعصبا
conservative carrier of all,
شركة الجوال الاكثر تحفظا,
said, "You can use any phone you want on our network."
قالت ,"يمكنك استخدام اي هاتف تريده على شبكتنا."
I love the Wired headline:
احب العنوان:
Pigs Fly, Hell Freezes Over
الخنازير تطير, الجحيم يتجمد
and Verizon Opens Up Its Network -- No. Really.
و فيريزون تفتح شبكتها-- لا يمكن
So everything is changing. We've entered
اذا الجميع يتغير. دخلنا
a new world of innovation, where the cell phone becomes your laptop,
في عالم جديد من الابتكارات,حيث اصبح الهاتف النقال هو حاسبك المحمول
customized the way you want it.
مخصص بالطريقة التي تريدها.
Every cell phone is unique. There is software that you can add on.
كل هاتف نقال متفرد. يوجد برامج يمكن اضافتها.
Can I do one more one-minute song? Thank you.
هل يمكنني تادية اغنية لدقيقة واحدة؟ شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Just to round it up -- this is the new Apple Power Music Stand.
فقط للتسهيل-- هذا هو جهاز الموسيقا الجديد من ابل
It's only three pounds,
انه يزن 1.3 رطلا
or 12 if you install Microsoft Office.
او 12 رطلا اذا قمت بتثبيت ميكروسوفت اوفيس
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Sorry, that was mean.
اسف, كان ذلك قاسيا.
This is a song I did for the New York Times website as a music video.
عملت هذه الاغنية لموقع صحيفة نيويورك تايمز كفيديو موسيقي
Ladies and gentlemen, for seven blissful hours
سيداتي سادتي, لسبع ساعات ممتعة
it was the number one video on YouTube.
كان الفيديو رقم واحد على اليو تيوب
And now the end is near.
والان النهاية قريبة
I'm sick to death
انا مريض لدرجة الموت
of this old cell phone.
بسبب هذا الجهاز النقال القديم
Bad sound, the signal's weak,
صوت سيئ, استقبال ضعيف,
the software stinks.
البرنامج عقيم
A made-in-Hell phone.
ذلك هاتف صنع في الجحيم
I've heard there's something new --
سمعت ان هناك شيئ جديد
a million times more rad than my phone.
اكثر روعة بملايين المرات من هاتفي
I too will join the cult.
أنا أيضا سانضم للجميع
I want an iPhone.
اريد اي فون
Concerns -- I have a few. It's got some flaws;
مخاوف-- فيه بعض العيوب,
we may just face it.
ربما يجب ان نواجهها
No keys, no memory card,
بلا مفاتيح, بلا شريحة ذاكرة,
the battery's sealed --
البطارية في الداخل--
you can't replace it.
لا يمكن استبدالها.
But God, this thing is sweet.
لكن يا الهي,هذ الشيء جميل.
A multitouch, iPod, Wi-Fi phone.
متعدد اللمس,,موسيقى,لا سلكي, هاتف
You had me from, "Hello."
جذبتني من أول وهلة "مرحبا"
I want an iPhone.
اريد اي فون.
I want to touch its precious screen.
اريد ان المس شاشته الرائعة
I want to wipe the smudges clean.
اريد ازالة القذارة
I want my friends to look and drool.
اريد اصحابي ان يحدقوا ويسيل لعابهم
I want to say, "Look -- now I'm cool"
اريد ان اقول, "انظرو-- الان انا ظريف"
I stood in line and I'll get mine.
سأقف في الطابور واحصل على واحد لي.
I want an iPhone.
اريد اي فون
For what is a man?
ما معنا الرجولة؟
What has he got? If not iPhone,
مامقيمة ماتملكه ان لم يكن اي فون
then he's got squat.
وسيجلس القرفصاء
It's all the things a phone should be.
هكذا يجب ان يكون الهاتف.
Who cares if it's AT&amp;T?
من يهتم ان كان من اي تي اند تي؟
I took a stand, paid half a grand!
وقفت في الصف, ودفعت خمسمائة دولار!
And I got an iPhone!
حصلت على اي فون!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you. Thank you very much.
اشكركم .اشكركم جدا.